# Ricardo Rodríguez Gambini | Senior Compositing Artist | 2021

richard@theshymonkey.com

+34.646.240.700

Elegible to work in the EU

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rrgambini

https://www.imdb.com/name/nm11139249

https://vimeo.com/iamtheshymonkey

#### **BACKGROUND**

+18 years of experience. I've worked both in house and freelance. I started to work as an editor in advertising and television. For the last 14 years I've worked mainly as a compositor looking for creative solutions for each project. Also, I've worked as an On-line editor and colorist, directing, coordinating teams of VFX artists and dealing directly with third party clients and my own clients. My work experience has given me the insight to meet everyone's expectations.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Compositing: Nuke, Fusion, After Effects, Photoshop

Rotoscoping and Planar Tracking: Mocha

Color Grading: DaVinci Resolve

Non Linear Editing: Avid Media Composer, Adobe Premiere, Final Cut, Nuke Studio

Pipeline/Sysadmin: Shotgun

## **EXPERIENCE**

EGG VFX | May 2020 - Nov 2020 | Dublin, Ireland FREELANCE SENIOR NUKE COMPOSITOR

TV Show "Intergalactic" Working in partnership with Milk VFX in London. I had the opportunity to work on a variety of tasks: from rotoscoping to complex cleanups, matte extractions from blue and greenscreens, look development of one of the vfx in Episode six and developed the template to distribute among artists. Compositing of different CGI elements (trees, hair, set extensions, glass, FX's, environments) into live action plates. During my time working on the show, I've delivered 40 final shots for 7 episodes in six months and worked on more than 55.

Screen Scene | Dec. 2019 - May. 2020 | Dublin, Ireland FREELANCE SENIOR NUKE COMPOSITOR

TV Show Kidding, Season 2, episode 10

Feature Film "Black Widow" (currently in post-production)

Feature Film "Flag Day" (currently in post-production)

Axis Studios | Sep 2019 - Dec. 2019 | Bristol, United Kingdom

FREELANCE SENIOR NUKE COMPOSITOR

Feature Film "Horizon Line"

Troll VFX | Sep 2019 | Tampere, Finland FREELANCE NUKE DIGITAL COMPOSITOR

Netflix TV Series "The Stranded"

Freelance VFX Compositor | Dec 2008 - present | Buenos Aires, Argentina / Madrid, Spain SENIOR COMPOSITOR | COLORIST | ON LINE EDITOR | VFX ON-SET SUPERVISOR

Working with different production companies for different clients in Argentina, EEUU, Russia and Spain such as Hyundai, Renault, Fox, Coca Cola, The Ad Council and Firestone among others.

Opium Effect | Dec 2008 - Sep 2019 | Munich, Germany FREELANCE VFX COMPOSITOR | COLORIST | VFX ON SET SUPERVISOR |

**Lightbox Academy** | Apr 2018 - Aug 2018 | Madrid, Spain NUKE INSTRUCTOR - MASTER IN VISUAL EFFECTS

Patagonik Film Group | Sep 2008 - Oct 2008 | Buenos Aires, Argentina DIGITAL COMPOSITOR

Feature Film "El Ratón Perez 2"

100 Bares Producciones | Oct 2005 - Mar 2006 | Buenos Aires, Argentina ROTO & PAINT ARTIST | POST PRODUCTION COORDINATOR

Tv Show: "Vientos de Agua"

- October to november: Roto paint artist (Episode 2)
- November to december: VFX compositor (Episodes 1, 3 and 4)
- November to march: Post production coordinator (Episodes 1 to 13)

Barraca Post | Feb 2008 - Dec 2008 | Buenos Aires, Argentina VFX COMPOSITOR | COLORIST

#### **EXPERIENCE**

ALT Broadcast Design | Aug 2006 - Dec 2007 | Buenos Aires, Argentina VFX COMPOSITOR | VFX ON SET SUPERVISOR

Alta Definición Argentina | Jun 2006 - Aug 2006 | Buenos Aires, Argentina COLORIST ASSISTANT | ON LINE EDITOR

Oct 1999 - Dec 2006 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

VIDEO TAPE OPERATOR | ASSISTANT OFFLINE EDITOR | OFFLINE EDITOR | ONLINE EDITOR | CAMERAMAN

During these years I worked in different companies both freelancer and inhouse, from small productions to bigger ones, mainly in advertising and television. I started to work as a video tape operator and then, moved into offline editing, first as an assistant and then doing my own cuts. Later I would become an Online Editor, a job that opened the doors to the compositing world.

Torneos y Competencias, La Corte, Universidad Nacional de Lanus, Bloomberg Television Network and Getty Images are some of the companies I've worked during these years.

## **EDUCATION**

Lightbox Academy | 2017 | Madrid, Spain

Sep 2017

VFX COMPOSITING WORKSHOP. Advanced techniques for VFX Artists by Miguel Macaya.

CGSOCIETY | 2015 | On Line Learning

**NOVEMBER AND DECEMBER** 

**BECOMING A BETTER ARTIST WORKSHOP by Robert Chang** 

FXPHD | 2009 | On Line Learning

**JULY AND OCTOBER TERMS** 

During these terms I worked to improve my knowledge and skills on Nuke

The Friends' Association of the National Museum of Fine Arts

Mar 2009 - Jul 2009 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

ART APPRECIATION SEMINAR

The Friends' Association of the National Museum of Fine Arts

Mar 2009 - Nov 2009 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

SHORT-TERM CAREER IN HISTORY OF ART

Universidad Nacional de Lanús | Jul 1998 - Dec 2001 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

POST-PRODUCTION TECHNICIAN

Metrovision Producciones | Aug 2000 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

POST-PRODUCTION COMPACT COURSE

Instituto Peruano de Informática y Tecnología | Sep 1999- Aug 1999 | Lima, Perú MULTIMEDIA PRODUCTION COURSE

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (native), English (fluent) and French (Basic level)

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request